dart.org 2018-06-30

# DART.org - Privacy Policy

**Privacy and Security Policy**

The Dallas Area Rapid Transit (DART), a Texas Regional Transportation Authority, maintains this site ([http://www.DART.org/](http://www.dart.org/)) as a public service. This policy describes DART's privacy practices regarding information collected from visitors to the site. It contains information about what information is collected and how that information may be used. This policy may be changed by DART at any time and without notice. Nothing contained in this policy statement shall be construed as specific legal advice. **Please note that, with certain exceptions, the majority of information collected or maintained by DART may be subject to the provisions of the Texas Public Information Act (Chapter 552, Texas Government Code) for disclosure to the public upon request.** One potential exception to disclosure is contained in §552.137 of the Texas Government Code, both of which state that an "e-mail address of a member of the public that is provided for the purpose of communicating electronically with a governmental body is confidential and not subject to disclosure ... [unless] the member of the public affirmatively consents to its release." **Please note that using the DART Store Online and/or DART's "Solicitations Online" shall constitute affirmative consent to release your e-mail address.** If you have questions or comments about the agency's privacy policy, please send e-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d1b4b4bdb0bc9195908385ffbea3b6).

The following is the privacy and security policy for this site (all pages starting with www.DART.org):

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**  
In the course of operating a web site, certain information may be collected automatically in logs or by cookies. A cookie is an electronic file that contains unique information a web site can use to track such things as passwords, lists of pages you've visited, and the date when you last looked at a specific page. It can be used to identify your session at a particular web site. A cookie is often used to identify the items selected for a specific shopping cart application or to verify that you have registered for use of particular portions of a web site. A cookie may also be used for site management functions. As a part of site management, information is collected for analysis and statistical purposes. This information is not reported or used in any manner that would reveal personally identifiable information. It will not be released to any outside parties unless legally required to do so in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings, or pursuant to any other legal or statutory request. Please note that this web site uses cookies for all of the, part of the, or for similar reason to the ones listed above.

The following information is collected as part of this site's management for analysis and statistical purposes:

  * **User Client hostname** \- The hostname (or IP address if Domain Name Server is disabled) of the user/client requesting access.
  * **HTTP header, "user-agent"** \- The user-agent information includes the type of browser, its version, and the operating system it's using.
  * **HTTP header, "referrer"** \- The referrer specifies the page from which the client accessed the current page.
  * **System date** \- The date and time of the user/client request.
  * **Full request** \- The exact request made by the user/client.
  * **Status** \- The status code the server returned to the user/client.
  * **Content length** \- The content length, in bytes, of the document sent to the user/client.
  * **Method** \- The request method used.
  * **Universal Resource Identifier (URI)** \- The location of a resource on the server.
  * **Query string of the URI** \- Anything after the question mark in a URI.
  * **Protocol** \- The transport protocol and version used.

**Information Collected from E-mails and Web Forms**  
If you send us an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, or fill out a form that e-mails DART this information, the personally identifiable information will only be used to respond to your request and analyze trends. We may redirect your message to another government agency that is in a better position to answer your question. Unless required by law, court order, or as legally required to do so in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings, we will not sell or release your e-mail address unless you affirmatively consent to the sale or release of the information. **Please note that using the DART Store Online and/or DART's "Solicitations Online" shall constitute an affirmative consent to release your e-mail address.**

**Security, Intrusion, Detection Language**  
For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this government computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, court order, or other legal proceedings, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Raw data logs are used for no other purposes and are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with the Texas State Library and Archives Commission. **Please note that, with certain exceptions, the majority information collected or maintained by DART may be subject to the provisions of the Texas Public Information Act (Chapter 552, Texas Government Code) for disclosure to the public upon request.** Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under, but not limited to, the Texas Penal Code Chapters 33 (Computer Crimes) or 33A (Telecommunications Crimes), and all applicable federal laws.

**Use/Release of Information**  
All information collected from the DART web site, including the summary server log information, e-mails sent to the web site, and information collected from web-based forms, may be subject to the Texas Public Information Act. One potential exception to disclosure is contained in Â§552.137 of the Texas Government Code, both of which state that an "e-mail address of a member of the public that is provided for the purpose of communicating electronically with a governmental body is confidential and not subject to disclosure ... [unless] the member of the public affirmatively consents to its release." **Please note that use of the DART Store Online and/or DART's "Solicitations Online" shall constitute an affirmative consent to release of your e-mail address.**

Produced and Maintained by the Dallas Area Rapid Transit.  
Copyright, 2020 Dallas Area Rapid Transit. All Rights Reserved.

Back to Top
